{
    "id": "ded8e5838956404c8564a2ac5430b853",
    "title": "Sequence of tenses",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "cf399738f39045c4b557d493b5e588ee",
            "title": "Sequence Of Tenses",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "If I ………………… rich I would donate a lot of money to charities.",
                    "description": "To talk about imaginary situations we use the simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "am",
                        "were",
                        "had been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you …………………….. me I would have told you.",
                    "description": "To talk about hypothetical situations we use a past perfect tense in the if clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "asked",
                        "have asked",
                        "had asked"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I have time, I ………………… a movie.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will watch",
                        "would watch",
                        "would have watched"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She said that it …………………… my last chance.",
                    "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
                    "answers": [
                        "is",
                        "was",
                        "will be"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Will you wait till I …………………..?",
                    "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, it is common to use a simple present in the subordinate clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "return",
                        "will return",
                        "would return"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You can stay here as long as you ……………………….",
                    "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, it is common to use a simple present in the subordinate clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "want",
                        "will want",
                        "wanted"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will call you when they ………………….",
                    "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, it is common to use a simple present in the subordinate clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "arrive",
                        "will arrive",
                        "would arrive"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She surprised everyone when she …………………….. the first prize.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "wins",
                        "won",
                        "had won"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will give 100 dollars to anyone who …………………… my puppy.",
                    "description": "Present tenses are used after question words and relative pronouns to refer to future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "finds",
                        "will find",
                        "would find"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We will reach there sooner than you ……………………",
                    "description": "In comparisons with as and than both present and future verbs are possible.",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "will do",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don’t know how I ……………………………….. there.",
                    "description": "When the main clause does not refer to the future, a future tense is required in the subordinate clause to refer to future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "reach",
                        "will reach",
                        "would reach"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}